CURRICULUM VITAE

Personal data

Name: L. Snoek (Lukas)

E-mail: L.Snoek@uva.nl / lukassnoek@gmail.com

Date of birth: 21 June 1991

Nationality: Dutch

Website: https://lukas-snoek.com

Software/code: https://github.com/lukassnoek

About me

I'm a PhD-student at the University of Amsterdam and I'm passionate about using **neuroimaging** to answer questions about mental processes, in particular, **how people perceive and process emotional information**. Next to doing research, I enjoy **teaching** (I am BKO-certified) and developing **open-source software** to make neuroscience and psychology more accessible, transparent, and reproducible (see my <u>Github page</u> for my software projects).

Research projects

In my PhD project, I work on a variety of projects that involve modelling psychological constructs and processes – ranging from gender and intelligence to emotion experience and empathy – on the basis of neuroimaging data using state-of-the-art analyses and methods. Below, a selection of these projects are outlined in which I fully or partly (e.g. only the data analysis) involved:

2018-present Computational (neural) models of facial expression perception

Topic: Investigating what information people use to infer

emotion from facial expressions using computational

modelling of behavior and UHF (7T) fMRI data.

Status: Analysis

Collab.: Dr. Steven Scholte, Dr. Suzanne Oosterwijk, prof. dr.

Agneta Fischer, dr. Tomas Knapen (VU uni.), Prof. dr. Philippe Schyns and dr. Rachael Jack (Uni. of Glasgow)

2016-2019 Confounds in MVPA

Topic: Investigating the influence and 'treatment' of

confounding factors in between-subject multivoxel

pattern analysis (MVPA).

Status: Published in Neuroimage

2016-present The brain basis of morbid curiosity

Topic: Analyzing and characterizing the brain basis of "morbid

curiosity" (curiosity for negative information, like

violence, mutilation, and harm) using task-based fMRI

Status: In review

Collab.: Dr. Suzanne Oosterwijk

2014-2017 **Shared States**

> Topic: Investigating the neural overlap between emotion

> > experience and emotion understanding.

Status: Published in SCAN

Code: github.com/lukassnoek/SharedSates

Collab.: Dr. Suzanne Oosterwijk & Dr. Steven Scholte

Teaching

2021-present Programming in Psychological Science - ResMas Psychology (UvA)

Developed a two-week Python/PsychoPy course. Materials available

at https://lukas-snoek.com/introPv.

2020-present The Psychology of AI - Psychology, BSc. (UvA)

> Course design and coordination of a new third-year BSc course. Topics: history of AI, symbolic AI, neural networks, behavioral data

science, and ethics.

2016-present Guest lectures – bachelor & (research) master Psychology (UvA)

Topics: computational (cognitive) neuroscience, artificial intelligence

(artificial neural networks), neuroimaging, statistics, Python

programming.

2016-present Supervision research projects/theses (BSc, MSc)

Supervision of research projects (6x), literature theses (1x), research

master theses (5x), and bachelor theses (5x).

2020 **BKO (Basis Kwalificatie Onderwijs)**

I obtained my higher education 'teaching certificate' (BKO) during my

PhD (10 April 2020), based on my teaching experience and qualities w.r.t. the two neuroimaging courses (see below) and

supervision of BSc and MSc students.

2017-present Neuroimaging: Pattern Analysis – Research Master Psychology (UvA)

> Developed from scratch, including course design, lectures, and computer labs. Topics: application of machine learning and

representational similarity analyses of neuroimaging data.

2013-present Neuroimaging: BOLD-MRI – Research Master Psychology (UvA)

> Responsible for supervising the labs, grading assignments, creating exams, and giving lectures (on the topics of multivariate methods and functional localization). Involved in the complete reorganization of the course (in 2016), creating a new set of 'computer labs' (programming

tutorials and assignments).

Open source software projects

2018-present exptools2 - https://github.com/VU-Cog-Sci/exptools2

The exptools2 package provides a wrapper around PsychoPy for developing easy, high-fidelity (neuroimaging) experimental paradigms.

2017 **Porcupine** - <u>github.com/TimVanMourik/Porcupine</u>

Porcupine is a graphical user interface to build reproducible neuroimaging pipelines. Users build their pipelines graphically and Porcupine generates the code necessary to execute the pipeline, as well as a complementary Dockerfile to incorporate users' pipelines in

a completely reproducible software environment.

2016-present bidsify - github.com/spinoza-rec/bidsify

'bidsify' is a tool to convert raw, unstructured MRI data to the BIDS format (bids.neuroimaging.io), allowing easy upload to Openneuro, which in turn helps researchers to make their data and

analyses more transparent and reproducible.

2015-present skbold - github.com/lukassnoek/skbold, skbold.readthedocs.io

The skbold package is a set of high-level tools for machine learning on BOLD-fMRI data. It is built on top of and complements Python's main machine learning library 'scikit-learn', providing an intuitive data-structure to represent pattern-based fMRI data, functionality for fMRI-specific feature preprocessing/selection/extraction, and tools for

feature visualization.

Education

2013-2015 University of Amsterdam – Research Master Psychology (MSc)

Major: Brain and Cognition (cognitive neuroscience)

Minor: Methodology and Statistics

Thesis: "On the dimensionality of neural representations"

Final grade: 10/10

GPA: 9.3 / 10 (graduated *cum laude*)

2010-2013 Amsterdam University College – Liberal Arts and Science (BA)

Major: Social science (emphasis on cognitive psychology)
Minor: Science (emphasis on behavioral neuroscience)
Thesis: "Moral emotions, attentional vigilance, and behavior:

Consequences of feeling (im)moral." Final grade: 95%.

GPA: 4.0. Graduated summa cum laude.

2003-2009 Johan van Oldenbarnevelt Gymnasium

Major: Social science course curriculum

GPA: 7.9 / 10.

Work experience

Jan 2021-present University of Amsterdam

Function: Assistant professor (Universitair docent)

Duties: 55% teaching (BSc/MSc psychology), 45% research.

Nov 2015-present University of Amsterdam

Function: PhD student

Project: Investigating computational models of face (expression) perception and their neural

implementation.

Promotor: Prof. dr. Agneta Fischer (social psychology)
Supervisors: Dr. H. Steven Scholte (brain & cognition) and Dr.

Suzanne Oosterwijk (social psychology)

2013-2015 Spinoza Centre for Neuroimaging (University of Amsterdam, FMG)

Function: Lab assistant / MR operator

Duties: Assisting researchers in the 3T (f)MRI scanning

procedure. Experience with executing studies using BOLD-MRI, structural MRI, arterial spin labeling and magnetic resonance spectroscopy. Responsible for weekly/monthly quality control of the Philips Achieva 3T scanner. Led an internal project on the signal quality of multiband (multislice-excitation) sequences versus

regular BOLD and DTI sequences.

2013-2014 **De Bijlespartner**

Function: Tutor statistics and biological psychology; Thesis

supervision of undergraduate psychology theses.

Duties: Helping university students with preparing for their

exams, both on an individual basis and for large groups (>10); supervision and assistance in writing, structuring,

and data analyses of undergraduate theses.

May-July 2013 Leiden University / KNAW: Academy Assistants Programme

Function: KNAW research assistant

Duties: Assisting in executing and data analysis of an fMRI

study on reward processing of visually presented stimuli of palatable food and attentional load.

Distinctions, scholarships, and grants

2019 Poster prize - NVP winter conference 2019 (€100)

For my poster on "AOMIC: a collection of publicly available population

imaging datasets".

2018 Grassroots education grant (with Noor Seijdel; €1000) Award to implement automatic grading/feedback using 'nbgrader' in programming education. 2017 Winner of the TransIP/Tweakers VPS challenge My application 'VoxelViz', a web-based app to interactively visualize MRI-data and results, won first place (prize: laptop + VR headset worth €3500) in a competition to develop an original and creative application on a virtual private server (VPS). More information at https://github.com/lukassnoek/VoxelViz. 2015 Thesis award – Research Master Psychology (€250) Award for the best thesis at the Research Master Psychology at the University of Amsterdam, 2014-2015 2015 1st place – ABC-BIC Neurolmaging Symposium (€ 250) Rewarded for the oral presentation of my Research Master internship research 'Decoding Emotions'. 2015 Travel stipend – University of Amsterdam (€ 1700) Granted several travel stipends to visit the prestigious Human Brain Mapping conference (Hononulu, HI, U.S.A.) to present my internship research. Stipends were awarded by the Brain & Cognition group (€1000), the International Office Psychology (€300), and the Graduate School of Psychology (€400). 2014 Honorable mention – Graduate Research Conference Psychology Received an honorable mention regarding the poster presentation of the Decoding Emotions project for receiving the most votes from staff members. 2013 Thesis of Highest Distinction – Amsterdam University College Highest award for bachelor theses at Amsterdam University College 2013 **KNAW** assistantship Paid assistantship for ambitious and talented students who pursue a career in science and can gain experience in doing research. It was used for setting up and executing an fMRI study at Leiden University under the supervision of Dr. Lotte van Dillen. 2011 Beta-Beurs Scholarship - University of Amsterdam (€ 4000) Received a grant of €4000 to spend on interdisciplinary research as part of my bachelor thesis. It was used in for an electrophysiological

Skills & proficiencies

study on attentional effects of moral emotions conducted in

collaboration with Leiden University.

Python Extensive Linux env Intermediate Git/Github Intermediate Intermediate R MATLAB Working knowledge **FSL** Extensive Bash Intermediate LaTeX Intermediate

Publications

Snoek, L., van der Miesen, M., Beemsterboer, T., van der Leij, A., Eigenhuis, A., & Scholte, H.S. (2020). The Amsterdam Open MRI Collection, a set of multimodal MRI datasets for individual difference analyses. *BioRxiv* preprint, doi: https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.06.16.155317.

Oosterwijk, S., **Snoek, L.**, Tekoppele, J., Engelbert, L. H., & Scholte, H. S. (2020). Choosing to view morbid information involves reward circuitry. *Scientific reports*, *10*(1), 1-13.

Hoogeveen, S., **Snoek, L.**, van Elk, M. (2020). Religious Belief and Cognitive Conflict Sensitivity: A Preregistered fMRI Study. *Cortex, 129*, 247-265.

van Elk, M., & **Snoek, L.** (2019). The Relationship Between Individual Differences in Grey Matter volume and Religiosity: A High-Powered Voxel-Based-Morphometry Study. *European Journal of Neuroscience*, Registered Report. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1111/ejn.14563.

Snoek, L.*, Miletic, S.*, & Scholte, H.S. (2019). How to control for confounds in decoding analyses of neuroimaging data. *NeuroImage*, *184*, 741-760.

Van Mourik, T., **Snoek, L**., Knapen, T., & Norris, D. (2018). Porcupine: interactive automatic pipeline software for neuroimaging analysis. See https://timvanmourik.github.io/Porcupine.

Oosterwijk, S.*, **Snoek**, **L**.*, Rotteveel, M, L. Barrett & Scholte, S. (2017). Decoding Emotions: Using MVPA to explore the neural overlap between emotion experience and emotion understanding. *Social, Cognitive, and Affective Neuroscience*, *12*(7): 1025-1035.

Invited talks, organized workshops and symposia, and public outreach

"Faces of Science" ambassadorship: science communication and public outreach, including (radio) interviews (NTR Radio 1, Focus Wetenschap), popular science talks, and blogging. See https://www.nemokennislink.nl/facesofscience/wetenschappers/lukas-snoek/.

Good Research Practices, round table discussion at ESCAN conference. Organized together with Dr. Suzanne Oosterwijk. Online, 3 July 2020.

Docker tutorial for scientists. OpenMR Benelux meeting, Nijmegen, 22 January 2018.

Multivariate Pattern Analysis. Invited speaker at the Spinoza Centre fMRI course, Amsterdam, 28 November 2018.

^{*} Authors contributed equally

Computational cognitive (neuro)science: what, why, and how? Symposium organized at the University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam, 16 February 2018 (with Jolien Francken and Lola Beerendonk).

Git(hub): version control for scientists. Workshop given for the lab of Dr. Simon van Gaal, University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam, 22 February 2018.

Invited speaker at Howl, a talkshow/dance performance/concert hosted by Spinvis, to discuss the nature of emotion; Purmerend, 11 November 2017.

MVPA of fMRI data in Python, a workshop organized for the "International Conference for Cognitive Neuroscience", Amsterdam, 5 August 2017 (with Steven Miletic). Materials available from lukas-snoek.com/ICON2017.

Decoding the brain and disease: promises and pitfalls of machine learning in science and medicine. Invited speaker at the Antoni van Leeuwenhoek (Nederlands Kanker Instituut), 19 September 2017, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.

Het (on)meetbare brein. Spui25: Proost op de Wetenschap, 12 Mei 2017, Amsterdam, The Netherlands (a popular science talk on the use of brain scans in science and society).

Conference presentations

Miletic, S. & **Snoek, L.** A universal method to deal with confounds in multivoxel pattern analyses. Poster presentation at the *International Conference for Cognitive Neuroscience* (ICON), 5 August 2017, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.

Snoek, L. Decoding Emotions: Using MVPA to explore the neural overlap between emotion experience and emotion understanding. *Associatie van Sociaal-Psychologische Onderzoekers (ASPO) conference,* 12 December 2015, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.

Snoek, L. Local vs. global brain representations. Poster presentation at the *NVP winter conference 2015*, 18 December 2015, Egmond aan Zee, The Netherlands.

Snoek, L. Decoding emotions in the brain. *ABC-BIC Neuroimaging Symposium*, 28 April 2015, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.

Snoek, L. Exploring the neural overlap between emotion experience and understanding. Poster presentation at the *Organization for Human Brain Mapping Conference 2015*, 17 June 2015, Honolulu (HI.), U.S.A.

Snoek, L. Patterns of emotion components. Presented at the *Brain and Emotion EASP* pre-conference, 8 July 2014, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.